Hey, Gin-san?!
(新八)ちょっと 銀さん！
先週 話してた映画化の件➡
The movie we mentioned
last week was for real?!
ﾎﾝﾄだったんですか!?
(銀時)あれ？ 疑ってたの？
What? You didn't believe me?
I mean, this show's been
nothing but lies...
だって 今まで この番組
ｳｿばっかついて…｡
That's not true.
(神楽)んなことないね｡
ｵｵｶﾐ少年だって➡
In the story of the Boy Who Cried Wolf,
a wolf actually showed up at
the end and the boy died.
最後は ﾎﾝﾄに ｵｵｶﾐ来て
死んじゃったよ｡
Same goes for this show.
この番組もしかりね｡
いや…
たとえが不吉すぎるんだけど…｡
Isn't that metaphor a little ominous?
In any case, we should celebrate.
まぁ とりあえず
めでたいってことにしとこうぜ｡
So this week, we have
something special.
んなわけで 今週は特別企画！
In celebration of the GinTama
anime becoming a movie!
And for DVD sales breaking one million!
The Second Character Popularity Poll!!
Here are the results!
(３人)大発表！
Except we're reusing the same CG.
(神楽)って言ってたわりには
ＣＧ 使いまわしね｡
いや でも すごいっすね｡
映画化だけじゃなく➡
Well, this is still amazing!
Not only has a movie been announced,
ＤＶＤの売り上げも 知らない間に
100万本突破してたんですね！
but we've sold over a million DVD's
without even realizing it!
More or less.
まぁな｡ 正確にいうと→
To be precise, we've
sold 878,236 copies.
If you round up, we've broken a million!
[Seasons 1-3 retail sales only
- Through Aniplex Research]
四捨五入で 100万本突破ね！
Hold it!
って おい！ 聞いたことねぇよ！
10万本単位の四捨五入！
I've never heard of rounding up
over 100,000 copies like that!
Stop sweating the nitty-gritty.
いちいち 細かいこと
気にすんなって｡
100,000 is NOT nitty-gritty.
いや 10万単位は細かくねぇし！
Plus, you said this is the
second popularity poll,
あ！ あと 第２回人気投票って
言ってたけど➡
第１回は いつ やってたｱﾙか？
but since when did we
ever do a first one?
The first one came before
there was an anime.
第１回は ｱﾆﾒ化する前に
もうやっちゃってたんだよ｡
The anime staff had the same question
so they went back through the manga.
ｱﾆﾒｽﾀｯﾌも同じこと思って 今回
ｺﾐｯｸｽ読み返して探したんだよ｡
And there it was in the ninth volume!
そしたら ありました！ ９巻に｡
They should do a better job of reading
the manga before they make an anime.
もうちょっと読み込んで
ｱﾆﾒ作るべきｱﾙな｡
And so, here are the results
of the Popularity Poll.
んなわけで
さっそく 人気投票の結果➡
Starting with 30th through
21st all at once!
30位から 21位をまとめて…｡
(３人)ｶｳﾝﾄ… ﾀﾞｳﾝ！
Count...
Down!
[Second Character Popularity
Poll: 30th-21st place]
[30 / Mutsu / Previously 15th / DOWN]
[30 / Kyojiro Nakamura / Previously - / NEW]
[29 / Prince Hata / Previously 18th / DOWN]
[28 / Abuto / Previously - / NEW]
[27 / Tsu Terakado / Previously - / NEW]
[26 / Ayame Sarutobi / Previously 20th / DOWN]
[25 / Ayumu Tojo / Previously - / NEW]
[24 / Tama / Previously - / NEW]
[23 / Matako Kijima / Previously - / NEW]
[22 / Justaway / Previously 19th / DOWN]
[21 / Kamotaro Ito / Previously - / NEW]
30位から 21位でした～｡
That was 30th to 21st!
さすが 前回から４年も経ってると
新ｷｬﾗが 続々とﾗﾝｸｲﾝしてますね｡
A four-year gap leads to lots
of new characters placing.
Then moving right along...
それじゃ引き続き 下位連中に
かけてる尺もないので➡
Since we can't waste time
on low-ranking losers,
20位から 11位まで…｡
(３人)ｶｳﾝﾄ… ﾀﾞｳﾝ！
here's 20th through 11th place.
Count...
Down!
[Second Character Popularity
Poll: 20th-11th place]
[20 / Mitsuba Okita / Previously - / NEW]
[19 / Bansai Kawakami / Previously - / NEW]
[18 / Taizo Hasegawa / Previously 13th / DOWN]
[17 / Tae Shimura / Previously 12th / DOWN]
[16 / Hideaki Sorachi / Previously 14th / DOWN]
ﾁｰｽﾞ蒸しﾊﾟﾝになりたい｡
I wish I could become a cheesecake!
[15 / Isao Kondo / Previously 10th / DOWN]
[14 / Kyubei Yagyu / Previously - / NEW]
[13 / Sadaharu / Previously 16th / UP]
[12 / Tatsuma Sakamoto / Previously 9th / DOWN]
[11 / Elizabeth / Previously 11th / STAY]
Huh?
あれ？ なんか ひとりだけ
ｾﾘﾌなかったですか？
Didn't one of them get to say something?
Sure.
まぁな｡ 原作者の特権だ｡
Special privilege of the original author.
Anyway, there are loads of new
characters showing up.
それより 新ｷｬﾗ 続々登場で
初期からの準ﾚｷﾞｭﾗｰが➡
It's interesting how most of the old regular
characters have been dropping.
軒並み順位を下げてるのが
え！ やば…｡
気になるね｡
What?! Crap...
And here's what you've
been waiting for...
それでは 注目のﾍﾞｽﾄ10！
10位から ４位｡
10th through 4th.
(２人)ｶｳﾝﾄ…｡
(３人)ﾀﾞｳﾝ！
Count...
Down!
[Second Character Popularity
Poll: 10th-4th place]
[10 / Tsukuyo / Previously - / NEW]
[9 / Sagaru Yamazaki / Previously 5th / DOWN]
[8 / Shinpachi Shimura / Previously 8th / STAY]
[7 / Kamui / Previously - / NEW]
[6 / Kagura / Previously 7th / UP]
[5 / Kotaro Katsura / Previously 6th / UP]
[4 / Shinsuke Takasugi / Previously 4th / STAY]
ﾀﾞｰｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ！ この私が
ﾊﾞｶ兄貴 その他新ｷｬﾗ有象無象に➡
Like I'd lose to my stupid brother and
the swarms of new characters!
負けるわけないね！ むしろ
順位 前回より上がってるね！
Hell, I even went up a spot!
They only served to make
me look better!
みんな 私の引き立て役よ！
それに引きかえ 新八…｡
Shinpachi, on the other hand...
You get all this screen time...
お前 こんなに出番多いのに…｡
(２人)何も変わんねぇのな｡
Yet nothing changed, huh?
いいから 続けて｡
それじゃ 残るは ﾍﾞｽﾄ３！
Just move on...
Now all that remains are the top three!
Here comes 3rd and 2nd place!
３位と２位を…｡
(２人)ｶｳﾝﾄ… ﾀﾞｳﾝ！
Count...
Down!
[Second Character Popularity
Poll: 3rd-2nd place]
[3 / Toshiro Hijikata / Previously 3rd / STAY]
[2 / Sogo Okita / Previously 2nd / STAY]
The mayonnaise/nicotine
addict and sadistic freak!
ﾏﾖ ｱﾝﾄﾞ ﾆｺ中と ドＳ野郎でした～｡
Only number one remains!
残すところも あと１位のみ！
Well, we all know who it is.
いや～ もう
わかってんだけどさ… 結果｡
Kind of embarrassing, yeah?
なんか 照れくさいっつぅか｡
でも 主役として当然というか…｡
Though it's only natural
as the main character.
But we still have to announce
it as part of the process.
でも 一応 発表すんのが筋だし～｡
So number one in the Second
Character Popularity Poll!
それでは 第２回ｷｬﾗｸﾀｰ人気投票！
[Cue card]
第１位 ｶｳﾝﾄ…｡
銀ちゃん！
Count...
Gin-chan.
Huh?
時間ｱﾙ！
え？ えぇっ!?
We're out of time.
Huh?
Huh?!
And here is the weekly
ranking for DVD sales.
それでは 今週のＤＶＤﾗﾝｷﾝｸﾞです｡
＜ とかく人間とは
番付が好きな生き物で➡
This in fourth place? What a laugh.
Humans are creatures
who love rankings.
Here are the top ten most watched
shows for the month.
何かといえば
順位をつけたがります｡
They have a tendency to
compare everything.
売り上げﾗﾝｷﾝｸﾞしかり
長者番付しかり｡
Like sales rankings...
Listing the richest people...
ﾃﾚﾋﾞの視聴率しかり
｢少年ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣のｱﾝｹｰﾄ制度しかり｡
Viewership ratings...
Shonen JUMP survey polls...
一時は この風潮に異を唱え
がんばった人は みな１位だと➡
For a while, there was a movement
against this trend.
There were schools that held sports
festivals without standings,
順位のない運動会を開く
学校なども現れましたが➡
claiming everybody who tried
hard should be first place.
現在では これもまた見直され…｡
But that's been abandoned now.
番付は 集団における
己の位置を知り➡
It's said that rankings are a way
to know your own standing,
so you can better improve yourself.
より高みを目指していくための
指標になるのではないか➡
という見方をされつつあります｡
しかし…＞
However...
＜ がんばっても がんばっても➡
If your ranking doesn't improve
after grueling hard work,
向上することのない
番付があったら➡
いったい
どうすればいいのでしょうか｡
what are you supposed to do?
向上心ではなく 敗北感しか
残らない番付があったとしたら➡
If your ranking leaves you feeling
defeated instead of inspired,
is there a point to that ranking?
果たして
それは必要なのでしょうか？
[8th place]
人気投票って… 必要ですか？
Are popularity polls really necessary?
Even if they are,
仮に必要だったとしても➡
is it necessary to publicly
announce the results?
それを人前にさらすのは
必要ですか？
８位から微動だに
しなかったﾎﾞｸは➡
If I couldn't budge from
my 8th place ranking,
必要ですか？＞
am I necessary?
["Screw Popularity Polls"]
(山崎)あれ？ 新八君｡
何やってんの？ こんなところで｡
Shinpachi-kun?
What are you doing here?
あっ… きゅ… 山崎さん｡
Oh, 9...
Yamazaki-san.
(山崎)今 ９位って
言おうとしたよね？
You were about to call
me 9th place, right?
別にいいけど
９位って言おうとしたよね？
Not that I care, but you were about
to call me 9th place, right?
仕事は？
いや…｡
Aren't you working?
Yeah, I'm just not in the mood...
今日は ちょっと
やる気がしなくて｡
そうか… ｷﾐも
１位と６位がいる職場だもんね｡
I see.
You work with 1st and 6th.
ｳﾁには ２位と３位｡
I've got 2nd and 3rd.
Oh... The same for you too, huh?.
あっ… じゃあ 山崎さんもですか｡
どや顔されるのがｲﾔで
前回も口には出さなかったけど➡
I can't stand the smug looks...
Captain Okita didn't say
anything last time either,
完全に 沖田隊長
どや顔してたから｡
but that look on his face...
普通の顔してても
なんか… 腹 立ちますよね｡
Even if they act normally,
it still pisses me off.
意識してんじゃねえの？
みたいな｡
Like, they're being conscious
about it, aren't they?
Deep down, they're being all proud
of themselves, you know?
心の中では 勝ち誇ってんじゃ
ねえの？ みたいな｡
神楽ちゃんも定春も
前回より順位上がったのに➡
Kagura-chan and Sadaharu
both went up...
ﾎﾞｸだけ 何も変わってなくて
８位のまま…｡
I'm the only one who didn't
change... Still at 8th.
いいじゃん 変わってないだけ｡
What's so bad about not changing?
ｵﾚ… 下がったよ｡
My rank went down.
あっ すみません…
そういうつもりじゃ…｡
Oh, sorry. That wasn't my intention...
Maybe the mohawk was a problem...
ﾓﾋｶﾝにされたのが
あれだったのかな…｡
ﾎﾝﾄ すみません…｡
I'm very sorry...
いや いいんだ 別に｡
No, it doesn't matter.
これぐらいが
ｵﾚには 居心地いいよ｡
Less stress this way.
My previous ranking was
odd to begin with.
前回が ちょっと
おかしかったんだよ｡
Must have been an organized vote,
or some under-the-table business...
どうせ組織票とか汚い力が
働いてたんでしょ｡
そ… そんなことありませんよ｡
Th-That's not true.
It's impressive, considering how
little screen time you get.
あんまり出番ないのに
逆に すごいじゃないですか｡
I have the second-most screen
time in the show...
ﾎﾞｸなんて １位の次に
たくさん出てるのに…｡
あの… ﾎﾞｸら なんか
悪いことしましたっけ？
Uh... Did we do something wrong?
いや たぶん
悪いことも いいことも➡
No... It's not an issue of right or wrong...
何もやってないのが
ﾀﾞﾒなんだと思う｡
The problem would be that
we haven't done anything...
引っかかりっていうのかな｡
いい意味でも 悪い意味でも➡
You've gotta catch their attention...
Whether in a good way or a bad way,
ﾌｯｸがないﾔﾂは
なんにも引っかからずに➡
if you can't hook the audience, you're
going to pass under their radar.
滑り落ちていってしまうんだよ｡
A hook...
ﾌｯｸか… 確かに ないですね ﾎﾞｸら｡
It's true that we haven't done that.
あっ すみません｡
一緒にしちゃって｡
Ah, sorry about grouping us together.
ああ いいよ｡
気 遣わないで 今日は｡
Nah, it's fine.
You don't need to be considerate today.
でも ﾌｯｸなんて
今さらつけても…｡
But it's too late to try to hook them...
正直 もうﾀﾞﾒかなっていう…
限界かなっていうのは感じてて｡
Quite frankly, I think it's over...
This is as far as I can go...
今さら 何やっても もう
ﾎﾞｸのｲﾒｰｼﾞは定着してるし➡
No matter what I do, my image's
been established.
ﾊﾞﾝﾀﾞｲﾅﾑｺは 完全に
ﾎﾞｸのこと なめきってるし…｡
And Bandai-Namco is clearly
looking down on me...
そもそも もっと
人気上げたいとか➡
Maybe it's just wrong for me wanting
to be more popular...
ｸﾞｯｽﾞ出したいとか➡
ﾎﾞｸが そんなこと
考えてること自体➡
Wishing for character merchandise
based off of me...
おかしいのかなみたいな｡ ﾊﾊ…｡
そのへんが ｺｲﾂ 必死だなって
ﾊﾞﾚてんのかな… みたいな｡
Maybe they've realized
how desperate I am...
ひいてんのかな… みたいな｡
Maybe it's turned people off...
新八君
８位 ９位って➡
Shinpachi-kun...
Is it so shameful to place 8th and 9th?
そんなに恥ずかしいことかな？
えっ？
Huh?
８位 ９位は
ｵﾚたち地味ｷｬﾗにとっては➡
Wouldn't 8th and 9th place be as good
as first for boring characters like us?
１位なんじゃないのかな｡
山崎さん…｡
Yamazaki-san...
仮に ｵﾚたちが
１位２位をとったとして➡
Even if we're to place 1st or 2nd,
それで正解かい？
would that be okay?
違うだろ？
No, right?
ｵﾚたちの周りには ｵﾚたちより
華のある人たちが たくさんいる｡
There are plenty of colorful
people, flowers, around us.
そして
その華を飾るためには 土が…｡
And those flowers need dirt,
a steppingstone, to bloom.
踏み台が必要なんだよ｡
ｵﾚたちは 人気ﾅﾝﾊﾞｰ１になんて
ならなくていい｡
We don't need to become number
one in a popularity poll.
ｵﾚたちは 踏み台ﾅﾝﾊﾞｰ１に
なればいいんだよ｡
We can be number one at
being their steppingstones.
Do the best you can in the role you've
been given, the position you hold...
自分の役割 立ち位置で
精一杯 がんばればいいんだよ｡
山崎さん… 山崎さんは
大人ですね｡
Yamazaki-san...
You're such an adult.
でも ﾎﾞｸは…｡
But I'm...
I'm no adult.
大人なんかじゃないよ｡
I was the same as you a while back.
ｵﾚも前は ｷﾐと同じだった｡
がんばれば… がんばれば
なんとかなると思ってた｡
I thought that if I worked hard...
If I worked hard...
I could place 1st...
きっと１位に…｡
山崎さん…｡
あれ？ おかしいな｡
Yamazaki-san...
Huh? That's odd...
もうずっと前に
あきらめてたはずなのに…｡
I gave up on that a long time ago...
なんで今になって こんな…｡
Why is this happening now?
Sorry!
ごめん！
(山崎)ｷﾞｬｰ!!
あっ！
やっ… 山崎さ～ん!!
Ya-Yamazaki-san!
H-Hang in there, Yamazaki-san!
し… しっかりしてください
山崎さん!!
いったい… いったい
何があったんですか!?
What...
What happened?!
《あっ！
や… 山崎さんの人気順位が➡
Yamazaki-san's ranking
is sinking like a rock!
急激に下がっていく！
これは… ﾊﾟﾝﾂを脱がされ
醜態をさらされたことで➡
His underwear being removed
to reveal a shameful sight
人気に変動が起きている！》
has led to a dramatic change
in his popularity!
Th-There's still... someone who hasn't accepted...
the results of the popularity poll...
に… 人気… 投票結果に
まだ納得していないﾔﾂがいる…｡
早く… ここから逃げろ…｡
Quickly... Run away...
ﾔ… ﾔﾂは 投票結果を➡
Th-That person intends... to forcibly
alter the results... of the poll...
ﾑﾘﾔﾘ 変えるつもりだ…｡
[Popularity Poll Arc]
に… 人気… 投票結果に
まだ納得していないﾔﾂがいる…｡
Th-There's still... someone who hasn't accepted...
the results of the popularity poll...
早く… ここから逃げろ…｡
Quickly... Run away...
ﾔ… ﾔﾂは 投票結果を➡
Th-That person intends... to forcibly
alter the results... of the poll...
ﾑﾘﾔﾘ 変えるつもりだ…｡
なっ… なんだって!?
Wh-What's that?!
Hurry...
早く… ８位だけは
地味ｷｬﾗ１位の座だけは➡
Protect your 8th position...
Th-The number one position
for a boring character...
ま… 守り通すん…｡
Y-You must... protect it at all... cost...
Ya-Yamazaki-san...?
山崎さん…｡
136位の山崎さん！
Yamazaki-san in 136th place!
《ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶな 今頃になって➡
I-Impossible!
How can you alter the results
of the popularity poll now?!
人気投票結果を
改変しようだなんて｡
もう ｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞ前で結果は
発表されているんだぞ｡
The results were announced before
the opening sequence!
今更そんなことをして
いったい何になるっていうんだ？
What could possibly be
accomplished now?!
とにかく みんなに知らせなきゃ｡
In any case, I have to let everyone know!
全員が標的だ！
They're all targets!
でもいったい誰に？
犯人が誰かもわからないのに…｡
But who did this?!
I don't know who it could be...
犯人は 山崎さんのﾊﾟﾝﾂを引き下げ
上位に食い込もうとしたんだ｡
The perpetrator removed Yamazaki-san's
underwear to climb the rankings...
間違いなく
山崎さんより下位の人物！
It must be someone ranked
below Yamazaki-san!
ｸｿｯ！ 候補が多すぎる！
Damn it!
There are too many candidates!
いったい誰を
信用したらいいんだ？》
Who can I trust?!
Th-That's...
あ あれは…｡
《25位｡ さっちゃんさん！
25th!
Sa-chan-san!
なぜ こんなところに｡
まさか さっちゃんさんが？》
Why is she here?
Could she have...?!
(さっちゃん)あなたね 人気投票
上位陣を下位に突き落とし➡
So you're the one who's trying to ruin the
popularity of the higher ranked characters
順位を変動させているのは｡
and stir up the rankings.
The perpetrator?! She's talking
to the perpetrator?!
《犯人？
犯人と喋っているのか？ 誰だ？》
Who is it?
見下げ果てた人ね｡
そんなことまでして➡
Despicable.
Will you be satisfied with a high
ranking through this method?
上位に食い込んで嬉しいわけ？
Who is it?!
《いったい誰が？》
Sarutobi-san, could you not
make odd accusations?
(お妙)猿飛さん 妙な言いがかりは
やめてくれませんか｡
そんなことを言うために
呼んだのなら帰っていいかしら｡
If that's your reason for calling
me out here, may I leave?
私 暇じゃないんで｡
I'm quite busy, you know.
S-Sis!!
《あっ 姉上！》
とぼけてんじゃないわよ｡
Don't play dumb.
Look above your head.
頭の上見てみなさいよ｡
順位繰り上がってんじゃないの｡
Your ranking's gone up.
それを言うなら あなたもでしょ｡
So has yours, for that matter.
よかったですね
ｷﾘのいいところにおさまれて｡
It must be nice to sit at
such a round number.
あっでも みんな繰り上がるから
意味ないのか｡
Oh, but it doesn't matter if
everybody's rank went up.
ごめんなさい｡ ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲとの
開きは永遠に埋まらないのね｡
Sorry, the gap between you and
Justaway will never go away.
まあ でも落ち込まないで｡
最近出番なかったですもんね｡
But don't beat yourself up about it.
You haven't had much screen time lately.
It's not your fault if you
lose to a lifeless object.
器物に負けても
そりゃ仕方ないわよ｡
あっ でもｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲも
出番なんて全然なかったのに➡
Oh, but Justaway hasn't had
any screen time either,
なんで猿飛さんより
上位なのかしら｡
so I wonder why it's a higher
rank than Sarutobi-san...?
で 出番さえあれば➡
I-If I had more screen time, Gin-san and I
would have finished in 1st and 2nd place.
銀さんと私で
ﾜﾝﾂｰﾌｨﾆｯｼｭも夢じゃなかったわよ｡
それに比べてお妙さん
あなたなに？
But look at you, Otae-san...
私よりたくさん出てたわよね｡
You had so much more screen
time than I did and yet...
なのに… あれ？ なんか
ｺﾞﾘﾗが見える｡ ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙｺﾞﾘﾗが見える？
Huh?
I see gorillas...
Twin gorillas?
何それﾍﾟｯﾄ？
あれ でも順位負けてない？
What are those? Pets?
Huh?
But you're ranked below them!
３人仲よく並んでなに？
Why are the three of you
lined up together?
ﾊﾞﾝﾄﾞでもやるんですか？
ﾄﾘﾌﾟﾙｺﾞﾘﾗ的な｡
Gonna start a band?
Gorilla triplets?
N-Not good...
《ﾔ ﾔﾊﾞｲ｡ なんか
ﾔﾊﾞｲ感じになってきたよ》
This is starting to look very bad...
おい 他はいい｡
Hey, I don't care about the rest.
あの野獣どもとだけは
ｾｯﾄにすんのはやめろ｡
But don't group me with those animals.
野獣って お妙さん｡
Animals? Otae-san...
原作者に向かって
それはないんじゃない？
You shouldn't say that
about the manga artist.
《いや ｱﾝﾀもﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙｺﾞﾘﾗとか
言ってたでしょうが！》
Wait, you also called them
twin gorillas, remember?!
今年はお妙さん あなたが
放置ﾌﾟﾚｲで決定ね ﾌﾌﾌｯ｡
Otae-san, you'll be the one
that's ignored this year!
あ～っ？ 一生出番
なくしてやろうか このﾒｽ豚が！
What?!
I'll make it so you never
show up again, whore!
上等じゃない！
あなたがいなくなれば➡
Bring it on!
Once you're gone, I'll get a little
more screen time, gorilla bitch!
私の出番も少しは増えるわ｡
ﾒｽｺﾞﾘﾗがぁ～っ！
Sis! Stop!
姉上 やめて！
(九兵衛)
２人とも そこまでだ｡
That's enough, you two...
Ky-Kyubei-san!
きゅ 九兵衛さん！
Kyu-chan...
九ちゃん｡
今はこんなところで➡
Now isn't the time to be fighting here.
争っている場合ではないはずだ｡
２人とも気づいているだろう｡
Both of you must be aware by now...
There's an insolent villain ruining the popularity of
the higher ranked characters for personal gain.
どこかに人気上位陣を
下位に突き落とし➡
上位に食い込もうとしている
不届き者がいる｡
Yes, yes! That's right!
《そうそう それそれ！ ｹﾝｶなんか
してる場合じゃないんですよ！》
This isn't the time to be fighting!
早急に何らかの対策を練らねば｡
We must prepare preventive measures.
That's right! That's right!!
《そうです そうです！
大丈夫そうだな｡
They should be fine.
このなかには犯人はいなさそうだ｡
None of them seem to
be the perpetrator.
よし ﾎﾞｸもまぜて…》
Okay, I'll join in...
この混乱に乗じて
一気に天守閣に攻め入ろう！
We must take advantage of the
chaos to attack the keep!
上位陣をすべて討ち取って
天下を制覇するんだ！
Eliminate every high-ranked
character and conquer all!
Wh-What is she talking about?!
《な 何言ってんのあの人！》
Wait, Kyu-chan! Are you serious?
ちょっと九ちゃん本気なの？
I know that I'm being unreasonable, but...
ﾑﾁｬを言うようで すまないが
やっぱり ﾎﾞｸは➡
I can't stand the fact that
Otae-chan isn't 1st.
お妙ちゃんが１位じゃないとｲﾔだ｡
あとは どうでもいい｡
The rest doesn't matter.
She isn't the perpetrator,
but she might as well be!
《犯人じゃねえけど
ほとんど 犯人だよ あの人》
In war, he who strikes first, wins.
戦の基本は先手必勝｡
幸い 上位陣は
順位が繰り上がっていない｡
Fortunately, the highest-ranked
characters didn't gain anything.
They haven't noticed this mess.
この騒ぎには
気づいていないはず｡
虚を突くは
今をおいて 他にはない｡
Now is our chance to
catch them off guard.
So you say, but you're the highest
ranked character here.
そんなこと言ったって この３人で
もっとも高順位は あなたなのよ｡
Won't you end up 1st in the end?
結局 あなたが
１位になって 終わりじゃない！
天下を統一したあかつきには
ﾎﾞｸは…｡
Once I have completed my conquest...
I will...!
自刃する所存だ｡
Take my own life.
Why are you risking your
life for a popularity poll?!
《人気投票に
どんだけ 命 懸けてんだ！》
You don't have to do that, Kyu-chan!
そんなことまで しなくていいわよ
九ちゃん！
Besides, I can't possibly do such
terrible things for personal gain.
それに 自分のためだけに
そんなひどいこと できないわ｡
Ranking in the top 10
is more than enough.
10位以内に入るくらいでいいわよ｡
《ほとんどの上位陣
殺るつもりだよ 姉上！》
She intends to take out most of
the higher-ranked characters!
そうよ 銀さんもいるんだし➡
That's right! Gin-san's included, so
we can set the cutoff at 8th place.
８位くらいまで
潰す感じにしましょ！
《ｷﾞﾘｷﾞﾘ ﾎﾞｸ 入ってるんですけど！
That barely includes me!
Couldn't you barely leave me out?!
ｷﾞﾘｷﾞﾘ はずしてくれても
いいんじゃないですか!?》
(お妙)でも やっぱり
やめておこうかしら…｡
But maybe we shouldn't...
Yes! That's good!
《そう それでいい！
平和にいきましょう》
Peace is good.
After all, that would include Kagura-chan
and Sadaharu-kun...
(お妙)だって 神楽ちゃんや…
定春君もいるし｡
《いや だから ﾎﾞｸは!?》
Hey, what about me?!
あら？
Oh?
この娘… 誰？
Who is this girl?
月詠!? 何？ これ！ 誰？ これ！
なんなのよ？ この娘!!
Tsukuyo? What is this?
Who is this? What's with this girl?!
なんで ９位になんか入ってるのよ
私たち 差し置いて！
Why is she ranked 9th ahead of us?!
ちょっと お妙さん…｡
Wait, Otae-san.
This girl had twice the votes you did!
この娘 あなたの２倍以上
票 取ってるわよ！ ｷｨｰｯ!!
O-Oh...?
へ… へぇ～！ あぁ…
結構 まぁまぁ かわいいものね｡
Ah, she's fairly cute, I guess.
まぁまぁって
この娘 ﾌｯｸだらけよ！
Fairly cute? This girl...
is loaded with hooks!
顔の傷のうえに さらに ｷｾﾙよ！
A scar on her face plus the pipe!
どんだけ 欲張ればいいのよ!!
なんなのよ!? この娘！
How greedy is she?!
What's wrong with this girl?!
東城の調べでは わっちなどの
郭言葉も使うらしい｡
According to Tojo's investigation,
she speaks with a classic
prostitute accent.
わっち!?
ちょっと なんなのよ!? この娘！
What?!
What's with this girl?!
お妙さん!! なんなの？ この娘！
Otae-san, what's with this girl?!
What?! What?!
O-Oh...? She's determined
to make an impression...
へ… へぇ～！
ｷｬﾗ立てに必死なのね｡
ﾑﾘして そんな言葉
使わなくてもいいのにね｡
There's no need to speak
in such a manner.
《なんか ちょっと怖い感じに
なってきたんですけど…》
This is starting to get scary...
And also according to
Tojo's investigation,
さらに 東城の調べでは
銀時に 胸をもまれたらしい｡
Gintoki groped her breast.
もむって どういうことよ！
Groped?!
What the hell?!
わっちだって
もまれたこと ないでありんす!!
I ain't never been groped, biotch!
《ねぇ なんか…
女のﾄﾞﾛﾄﾞﾛした感じに➡
Say, this is starting to get ugly...
なってきてんですけど》
Oh...?
へぇ… あぁ だから 銀さん
最近 ﾂｲてないんじゃない？
Ah, that's why Gin-san's
been down on his luck.
この娘 絶対 ｻｹﾞﾏﾝよね｡
This girl must be a bad luck woman.
本当だわ｡
この娘 ｻｹﾞﾏﾝ面でありんす！
You're right.
Her face screams bad luck, biotch!
絶対 そうよね！ 関わったら
ろくなことにならないﾀｲﾌﾟよ｡
Right? Nothing good can come from
getting involved with this type.
かわいそうに！
なに!?
Poor thing.
What, this is the bad luck
woman I've heard about?
これが 天下に聞く
ｻｹﾞﾏﾝというものか｡ ほう…｡
Coming from three of the
worst bad luck women!
《天下の ｻｹﾞﾏﾝ３人娘が
何 言ってんだ！
やめろ!! こんなﾄﾞﾛﾄﾞﾛの劇
これ以上 見たくねえ！》
Stop it!!
I don't want to see any
more of this ugly act!!
ちなみに 東城の調べでは➡
And according to Tojo's investigation,
177話から181話まで この娘が
ほぼ 出ずっぱりらしい｡
she was featured from episodes
177 through 181.
Oh...?
へぇ… じゃあ 182話以降は…｡
Then starting from episode 182...
もう 出なくていいわよね！
She shouldn't need any
more screen time!
《姉上!! さっちゃんさん!!
やめて！ 止めて 誰か!!》
Sis! Sa-chan-san!
Stop! Somebody stop them!!
そうか｡ じゃあ まず
ここから攻め落とすか…｡
I see...
Then we should attack her first?
お妙ちゃん どこに行くんだ？
Otae-chan, where are you going?
I'll let the two of you handle her.
そっちは２人に任せるわ｡
I'm going to deal with the source.
私は根本を絶ちにいく｡
根本？
Source?
これ以上 女ｷｬﾗが増えて
出番がなくならないように…｡
To make sure there aren't any more new female
characters taking away my screen time...
15位のｺﾞﾘﾗ 潰してくる！
I'll go crush the gorilla in 15th.
《ｺﾞﾘﾗはﾀﾞﾒ!! この漫画
もとい ｱﾆﾒ 終わる！》
Not the gorilla!
This manga, I mean, anime will end!
This is bad!
《まずい！ まずいことになった!!
This is getting really bad!
On second thought, I shouldn't
be searching for a perpetrator,
考えてみたら 犯人探しどころか
どいつもｺｲﾂも➡
when I'm surrounded by all these egotistical people
who could become perpetrators at any minute!
いつ 犯人になってもおかしくない
ｴｺﾞの塊みたいな連中だった！
どうする!?
どうすれば 止められる!?
What do I do?!
What do I do to stop this?!
I need someone's help!
誰が 力になってくれる？
この状況で 絶対に
犯人になりえない人間は…｡
The one person who would never become
a perpetrator in this situation...
あっ！
１位のｱｲﾂに頼るしかねえ！》
I'll have to rely on the guy in 1st!
あっ！
あ… あれ？
Huh?
な… なんだ？ これ！
Wh-What is this?!
なんか おかしく…｡
Something's wrong...
ﾍﾛﾍﾛに…｡
All distorted...
あれ？ これって まさか…｡
Is this...
Could it be...
[Please wait one moment.]
空知 やられた!!
Sorachi's been taken out!!
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
And so, since the original
author's been taken out,
the GinTama anime will be off next week.
[Or so we thought, but that wasn't doable. You should give us a break every once in a while, TV Tokyo.]
[The original author's gone and we're out of stock footage. Can we use backgrounds only for the entire episode next week?]
[See you next time.]